Rafia Khandaker

(516) 491-4984 | RafiaKhandaker@gmail.com | New York, NY Portfolio | LinkedIn | Github | Blog

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Developer with a passion for continued learning, experienced in JavaScript, React, Ruby, Rails, and SQL. A background in Social Media marketing, I realized my joy for creating content that resonates with people. Through programming, I find satisfaction thinking critically to solve technical problems and improve usability. I bring excellent communication and organizational skills to team settings, a proven project management aptitude, and strong sense of self-motivation to drive a vision to fruition in both an aesthetic and practical manner.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Full Stack: JavaScript, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, SQL, React, Active Record, PostgreSQL, SQLite, RESTful APIs, Git

Design: Canva, Illustrator, Lightroom, Photoshop, HTML/CSS, Figma, Material UI

Social Media: Khoros, Google Analytics, Digimind, Facebook Analytics, Pinterest Analytics

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Concert Buddy - Github | Demo

View concerts from your favorite artists, add yourself to a list of attendees, and meet fellow concertgoers in New York City.

- Implemented authentication and password protection in Rails for users to sign-up or login using tokens.
- Designed a React frontend and cohesive styling elements through Figma.
- Built out a full CRUD functionality for users to personalize their accounts.

FiDi Dining Guide - Github | Demo

Single-page application with searchable listings of restaurants, cafes, and bars in the Financial District, Manhattan.

- Constructed client-side routes with React Router and RESTful routing conventions.
- Features search function to filter by type of establishment, street address, or name.
- Developed an API of location listings in a SQLite database with the ability to persist data for new listings.

Poemland - Github

Writing-prompt application that provides users randomized lyrics off of which to base a poem and view others entries.

- Utilized a Ruby Sinatra API backend using Active Record to access database information.
- Generated a React frontend with ability for users to create an account that saves their daily poems.
- Incorporated forms to create and edit poems that persist to the backend.

EXPERIENCE

Publishers Clearing House Jericho, NY

Social Media Coordinator

06/2016 - 07/2022

09/2018 - 07/2022

- Improved and modernized brand styling through eye-catching visuals and engaging copy to millions of followers across Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, YouTube and Pinterest.
- Increased Instagram impressions and engagement 100%, video views 50%, and followers 20% year-over-year by regularly translating metrics in performance reports and adjusting social strategy accordingly.
- Advised a customer service team with other team leads ahead of new promotions and addressed user concerns.
- Led creative initiatives for e-commerce promotions on Facebook Shops and A/B testing for acquisitions campaigns.
- Mentored a rotation of interns oversaw training on social media analysis tools and trend research and execution.

Project Management Intern

06/2016 - 08/2018

- Supported the Project Manager on the Interactive Development team by assisting with mobile application launches, site updates, email campaigns, video shoots, event promotions, and social media initiatives.
- Launched and tracked 40-70 projects weekly, managing resources across a team of 25-30 creatives and prioritizing project tasks and deadlines.
- Onboarded users to workflow management platforms and resolved technical issues.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School New York, NY

08/2022 - 11/2022

Full Stack Development: Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Stony Brook University Stony Brook, NY

Bachelor of Science: Information Systems, Specialization in Business and Economics